So now that we have seen the application and we have seen how application can be hackable, now we will
see the actual power of Mifare classic cards and see the memory organization of these cards first.
Right?
So we will start with the memory organization.
So one came a classic card has 1024 bytes all together, right?
And this memory is divided into logical sectors and blocks.
So we will come what sector and block is in a moment.
But for now you should know that the memory size is 1024 bytes and this memory is divided into sectors
and blocks.
So there are total 16 sectors in each mifare card, and these sectors are from 0 to 15.
So 0 to 15 altogether are 16 sectors.
And in each sector there are four blocks.
So there are 16 sectors altogether, and in each sector there are four blocks.
So you have to remember this.
And after that, you have to know that there are 16 bytes in each block.
Right.
So let me repeat it one more time.
So there are 16 sectors starting from zero till 15.
And then in each sector there are four blocks and each block is of 16 bytes.
So this is the format I'm going to show you in a moment as well.
But you have to remember this, right?
And after that, there are two keys.
Key A and B in each sector.
So let's just first see the sectors and blocks so it will make more sense.
Then we'll come on Keys.
So as you can see it over here.
The sectors blocks.
This is a complete diagram of one card.
So I'll go through this diagram one by one.
The things were the things in this diagram.
So first of all, let's just look at the sectors.
So there are 16 sectors, as you can see.
So till 15.
You can see the first block.
And in each sector there are four blocks, right?
So starting from zero one, two, three, these are four blocks from 020 till three.
And if you look at sector one, still there are three blocks starting from zero one, two and three.
So altogether these are four blocks.
So so this is the same case in each sector, right?
If you look at sector five, sector six, there are four blocks in each sector.
So let's just look at sector two for now.
Just just to check.
So over here, you can see in sector two, there are four blocks zero one, two and three, right.
So zero one and two.
The first three blocks are data blocks and data block, which we can write anything, whatever data
we want.
We can write any data in data block.
Uh, but the third or the fourth, I should say the fourth block in each sector.
The fourth block in each sector has access rights, so it contains key A and key B.
So these concepts are a little hard to digest.
I would suggest that you should watch this video more than once so that these concepts get clear to
you.
So let me repeat it one more time.
So over here you can see there are four blocks and the fourth block is the access block.
So in access block, there are key A and key B.
I'll show you the key A and key B in a moment.
Let's just go to the presentation one more time so you can see over here as well.
There are two keys.
Key A and B in each sector.
Right.
So this third sector, which you can see.
Sorry, the fourth sector, which which you can see in in red color is known as sector trailer.
So the name of this specific block is known as sector trailer.
So this sector trailer is in each sector.
Right.
So the fourth block in each sector is a sector trailer.
Now let's just come to the concept of keys.
So there are two keys, as I told you before, Key A and key B.
So key A is of fixed part the first six bytes.
Is a.
Over here, you can see the first six bytes is key.
A then last six bytes is key B and the middle four bytes are known as excess bits.
We will go to the concepts of excess bits and key A and key B in very detail in coming videos.
This video is just to clear your concept about the memory structure, right?
So don't worry if you don't get or don't digest all the things in this video, you will be comfortable
once you will see all these things in action, right?
So just remember these things for now.
So key A is of six bytes.
The first six bytes is key, A then the last six bytes.
It's key B and the middle four bytes are excess bits.
So let's just repeat all the things together.
So there are 16 blocks.
Sorry, there are 16 sectors in each in each Mifare classic one key card starting from zero till 15.
So altogether these are 16 sectors and then each sector contains four blocks, right?
Starting from zero till three and the fourth block, which is number three because we are counting with
zero.
So the fourth block is a access block.
This block is also known as Sector Trailer.
And in sector trailer, there are three things key A, key B and the access bit.
So the first six bytes are key.
A.
And the last six parts are key and the four bytes are excerpts.
Right.
So this is the concept of one memory card of Mifare Classic.
And now one more thing.
Authentication is required, right?
So if you want to read block, let's suppose sector two and you want to read sector two and block one
of sector two, you must authenticate first either with key A or key B, We will come to this concept
in a later video through which key you can access.
But authentication is required if you want to access anything, any data from from any sector or any
block, right?
So the authentication is required to access any data in any sector.